Women in Argentina, V: Pamphlets, 1982-1998: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library
Women in Argentina, V: Pamphlets
1982-1998
MICROFILM 11586
LAE084
Princeton University. Library. Dept. of Rare Books and Special Collections One Washington Road Princeton, New Jersey 08544 USA
2 microfilm reels
Princeton University. Library.
This microfilm consists of pamphlets published between 1982 and 1998 by community and national organizations as well as government agencies covering women-related issues in Argentina.
The Princeton University Library has developed numerous collections of Latin American ephemera that are unique in their depth and scope. Privileging the popular voices of the region, the collections document numerous political and social movements, and a wide variety of key socioeconomic and cultural developments. Some particularly well-documented topics are grassroots organizing, human rights, electoral politics, indigenous issues, women and gender issues, youth, the environment, health, education, and religion. Types of primary materials collected include pamphlets, non-commercially produced and distributed serials, flyers, posters, working papers, government publications, and other non-traditional formats. Most of the documentation in the collections was produced after the mid 1960s by Latin American nongovernmental organizations of all types, interest groups, political parties, research institutes, and government agencies.
The intensive collecting of ephemera was initiated by Barbara Hadley Stein, the University's first Bibliographer for Latin America, Spain and Portugal (1966-1977). She sought to document some of the major political developments of the period, including the rise to power of military dictatorships, coup d'états, the institutionalization of the Cuban Revolution, and the popular responses to those developments. Her successor, Peter T. Johnson (1977-2003), expanded the geographic and thematic scope of the collections and systematized the process of organizing, cataloging, and preserving them. Intensive collecting in this area continues to this date.
Over the years, materials have been grouped and organized by country or region, and by topic or subject area. Once collections are fully organized, they are cataloged and microfilmed. A complete list of collections appears in the Guide to the Princeton University Latin American Microfilm Collection (Wilmington, DE: Scholarly Resources, 1993) and subsequent supplements. Many of the collections' finding aids are available online. Original print materials have been preserved in many cases.
This collection consists of pamphlets published between 1982 and 1998 by community and national organizations as well as government agencies covering women-related issues in Argentina.
The Latin American ephemera collections are open for research use.
Microfilm can be consulted in Microforms Service, Firestone Library (http://firestone.princeton.edu/microforms/).
Please consult with the Department of Rare Books and Special Collections about having those portions of the collection that are stored off site recalled to the Department for your use. This process normally requires 48-72 hours notice.
MICROFILM 7662 (Master printing copy. Available for reproduction only.)
Bellotti, Magui. Feminismo y el movimiento de mujeres, Argentina, 1984-1989. 1989.; Oddone, María Elena. Prensa feminista. 1990.; Blanco, Justo Horacio. Encuesta sobre oportunidades perdidas en el puerperio. 1993.; Bonafini, Hebe de,1928-. Discursos de Hebe Bonafini en los actos de repudio al golpe de estado. 1995.; Bonder, Gloria. Participación de las mujeres en las noticias. 1996.; Yelicic, Clori. Mujer en la Constitución de la ciudad de Buenos Aires. 1996.; Madres de Plaza de Mayo (Association); Women -- Argentina.; Women -- Employment -- Argentina.; Women in politics -- Argentina.; Women -- Health and hygiene -- Argentina.; Abortion -- Argentina.; Women's rights -- Argentina.; Women -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Argentina.; Women -- Crimes against -- Argentina.; Fertility, Human -- Argentina.; Birth control -- Argentina.; Non-governmental organizations -- Argentina.; Women -- Argentina -- Societies, clubs, etc.; Latin American studies
- Miscellaneous Publications, 1982-1998; File 1:; 27
- Abortion, 1990-1993; File 2:; 1 item
  - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1990-1993; 7
- International Women' s Day, 1992-1997; File 3:; 1 item
  - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1992-1997; 24
- Madres de Plaza De Mayo, 1988-1997; File 4:; 1 item
  - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1988-1997; 34
- Violence, 1989-1998; File 5:; 1 item
  - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1989-1998; 10
  - Violencia Contra Las Mujeres: Informes de Investigación (CECYM), 1995; 3
- Organizations, 1980-1998; File 6:; 1 item
  - ACP (Amas de Casa del País), 1992-1994; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1992-1994; 7
  - AIMA (Asociación Internacional de Mujeres Argentinas), 1991-1993; 1 item
    - Boletín no 59-60, 1991 68-69, 1993, 1 item
  - Centro de Estudios de la Mujer, 1994-1997; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1996-1997; 3
    - Satelite Evita Dossier de Prensa no 1-5, 1994-1995; 1 item
    - Serie Mujer y Comunicación Cuadernillo De Trabajo no 1, 3-4, 1994-1995; 1 item
  - Consejo de la Mujer, undated; 1 item
    - Conocer, Prevenir, Curar, undated; 3
  - Consejo Nacional de la Mujer, 1985-1997; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, circa 1985-1997; 7
    - Mujeres Trabajando Boletín Informativo no 1-2, 1993-1994; 1 item
    - Serie Pasos y Vuelos no 1-3, 1994; 1 item
    - Servicio de Orentación Laboral para las Mujeres no 1-3, 1995; 1 item
  - FEIM (Fundación para estudio e investigación de la mujer), 1991-1996; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1991-1996; 16
  - Fundación TIDO Centro de Acción Particitiva: Casa de la Mujer, undated; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 2
  - Instituto Social u Político de la Mujer, 1992-1998; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, undated; 1992-1998; 13
  - Organización Feminista Argentina, 1980-1986; 1 item
    - Persona: Revista Feminista Año I no 3-4, 1980Año II no. 6-9, 11, 1981-1982Año I no I, 1986, 1 item
    - Persona: Boletín Feminista Bimensual no 12, 17, 1980; 1 item
  - PSP (Partido Socialista Popular) Bloque de la Unidad Socialista, 1994-1996; 1 item
    - Miscellaneous Publications, 1994-1996; 3